Your vision of the world will change forever.
Blindness is a drama, mystery, science fiction
film directed by Fernando Meirelles.
When a sudden plague of blindness devastates a city, a small group of the afflicted band
together to triumphantly overcome the horrific conditions of their imposed quarantine.
Doctor's Wife, played by Julianne Moore.
Doctor, played by Mark Ruffalo.
Man with Black Eye Patch, played by Danny Glover.
Bartender / King of Ward Three, played by Gael García Bernal.
Accountant, played by Maury Chaykin.
Woman with Dark Glasses, played by Alice Braga.
Blindness is a 2008 English-language thriller film about a
society that suffers an epidemic of blindness.
The film is an adaptation of the 1995 novel of the same
name by the Portuguese author José Saramago.
The film was written by Don McKellar and directed by Fernando Meirelles, starring
Julianne Moore as the doctor's wife and Mark Ruffalo as the doctor.
Saramago originally refused to sell the rights for a film adaptation, but the producers were able to
acquire it with the condition that the film would be set in an unnamed and unrecognizable city.
Blindness premiered as the opening film at the Cannes Film Festival on May 14, 2008, and was released
in Canada as part of the Toronto International Film Festival on September 6, 2008.
The film explores themes of blindness and impaired vision,
based on novel or book, fight, society, asylum.
The tone is emotional and uplifting and mind_bending.